Finding aid for the Gene Roddenberry Star Trek Television Series Collection PASC.0062
UCLA Library Special Collections
- PRODUCED EPISODES
  - THE TROUBLE WITH TRIBBLES (Prod# 42)
    - 1) First Draft Teleplay, 6/30/67, w/annotations, 69 pgs. 2) First Draft Teleplay, 7/19/67, 71 pgs. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (68), DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 72 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Production Materials: Photographic effects (2). Total Items: 2 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Financial Materials: Contract Request Form (1). Total Items: 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 7/5/67 - 4/3/68. Total Items: 9 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Bay, Don R. * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - TURNABOUT INTRUDER (Prod# 79)
    - 1) Revised story outline by Gene Roddenberry, 4/30/68, w/annotations, 23 pgs. 2) Revised story outline, 4/30/68, w/annotations, 26 pgs. 3) Story outline, 5/8/68, 21 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (6). Total Items: 6 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Financial Materials: Contract Request Form (1), Weekly Production Summary (2), Estimated Finished Cost (3). Total Items: 6 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 4/15/68 - 12/16/68. Total Items: 4 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Freiberger, Fred (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - THE ULTIMATE COMPUTER (Prod# 53)
    - 1) Teleplay by Laurence N. Wolfe, 11/9/67, w/annotations, 68 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Wolfe, Laurence N. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (3). Total Items: 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 10/13/67 - 12/13/67. Total Items: 18 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Fontana, D.C. * Robertson, Stanley * Wolfe, Laurence N. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - THE WAY TO EDEN (Prod# 75)
    - 1) Story Outline by D.C. Fontana, 7/11/68, 14 pgs. 2) Outline by D.C. Fontana, 8/27/68, 15 pgs. 3) Teleplay by D.C. Fontana & Arthur Heinemann, 11/11/68, w/annot., 65 pgs. 4) Final teleplay by D.C. Fontana & Arthur Heinemann, 11/12/68, 40 pgs. (Inc.) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Fontana, D.C. * Heinemann, Arthur (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (5). Total Items: 5 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, 9/9/68 - 11/27/68. Total Items: 5 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Bays, Donald W. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Production Materials: Shooting Schedule (9), Photographic Effects (3), Daily Production Reports (7), Call Sheets (5). Total Items: 24 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (5), Estimated Finished Cost (7). Total Items: 37 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - WHAT ARE LITTLE GIRLS MADE OF? (Prod# 10)
    - 1) Story outline by Robert Bloch, n.d., 17 pages, plus 2 additional pages w/alternate ending. 2) Revised version, 3/28/66, 14 pages, 2 copies, one w/annotations. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bloch, Robert (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1) First draft teleplay by Robert Bloch, 04/26/66, 60 pgs. 2) Revised draft, 7/25/66, in 2 parts, 66 pgs, missing pages 33 - 37. 3) Draft, n.d., w/annotations, 63 pgs. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Script materials: Revisions, loose pages (141), Comments on teleplay (2), DeForest Research (8), Narration (2). Total Items: 153 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Production materials: Editing Notes (2), Credits (3, 3 copies), Revised Credits (3, 4 copies), Revised Airing Sequence (3, 2 copies), Shooting schedule (9), Call sheets (14), Cast List (2), Daily Production Reports (9). Total Items: 63 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Inter-Office Memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/29/66 - 9/28/66. Total Items: 47 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Bloch, Robert * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene * Solow, Herb * Robertson, Stanley * Theiss, Bill * Black, John D.F. * Jefferies, Matt * Kubichan, Jon (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials: Photo effects (1), Production budget report (3), Daily Budget Reports (9). Total Items: 13 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE (Prod# 2)
    - 1) Detailed Synopsis, n.d., 7 pgs. (2 copies) 2) Final Revised Draft of Teaser by Samuel A. Peeples, 2 pgs. (2 copies) 3) Final draft teleplay, 6/26/65, w/annotations, 70 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Peeples, Samuel A. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (42), Narration, Wild Lines (14), DeForest Research (2), Comments on story outline (6, 2 copies), Teleplay Notes by James Goldstone (2), 2nd draft notes by James Goldstone (5). Total Items: 77 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Production Materials: Production Reports (11), Photographic Effects (58) and budget (3), Special Effects Comments (52), Matte Shots (2, 2 copies), Shooting Schedule (13). Total Items: 141 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Production Materials: Credits (10), Dubbing Schedule (1), Cast and crew (12), Call Sheets (9), one-page budget (1). Total Items: 33 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/27/65 - 4/11/66. - Letter of appreciation, 13 August 1965 to cast and crew (26) Total Items: 72 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Butler, Bob * Katz, Oscar * Bay, Don R. * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Perlstein, Ed * Goldstone, James * Lynn, Harvey * Solow, Herb (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Financial Materials: Overage Reports (8), Daily Budget Reports (1), Production Budget Reports (5), Andrea Dromm Contract (3), Paul Fix Contract (3), Lloyd Hanes (2). Total Items: 22 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - WHO MOURNS FOR ADONAIS? (Prod# 33)
    - 1) Story Outline by Gilbert A. Ralston, 3/8/67, 14 pgs. 2) Teleplay, 4/7/67, 63 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Ralston, Gilbert A. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Script Materials: Revisions, loose pages (45), DeForest Research (5). Total Items: 50 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Production Materials: Shooting schedule (5), Photographic effects (4). Total Items: 9 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/23/67 - 5/22/67. Total Items: 58 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Roddenberry, Gene * Justman, Robert * Coon, Gene * Fontana, D.C. * Robertson, Stanley (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Financial Materials: Contract Request Form (1), Production Budget Reports (2), Daily Cost Reports (5). Total Items: 8 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - WHOM GODS DESTROY (Prod# 71)
    - 1) Story Outline by Lee Erwin, 7/18/68, 7 pgs. 2) Teleplay, 8/16/68, 53 pgs. 3) Revised teleplay, 8/28/68, 57 pgs. 4) Revised teleplay, 9/17/68, 61 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Erwin, Lee (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (4). Total Items: 4 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Messerschmidt, Jean * Robertson, Stanley (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (4), Shooting Schedule (7), Photographic Effects (2), Daily Production Reports (8), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 27 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (7), Estimated Finish Cost (12). Total Items: 44 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - WINK OF AN EYE (Prod# 68)
    - 1) Story Outline by Lee Cronin, 3/11/68, 12 pgs. 2) Story Outline by Lee Cronin, 3/22/68, 14 pgs. 3) Teleplay by Arthur Heinemann, 8/27/68, 60 pgs. 4) Teleplay by Arthur Heinemann, 9/2/68, 60 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Cronin, Lee (pseudonym for Gene Coon) * Heinemann, Arthur (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (9). Total Items: 9 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 3/18/68 - 10/22/68. Total Items: 13 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Robertson, Stanley * Roddenberry, Gene * Messerschmidt, Jean (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Production Materials: Credits Breakdown (4), Shooting Schedule (6), Photographic Effects (4), Daily Production Reports (6), Call Sheets (6). Total Items: 26 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Financial Materials: Budget Report (1), Budget Worksheets (24), Weekly Production Summary (9), Estimated Finish Cost (16). Total Items: 50 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - WOLF IN THE FOLD (Prod# 36)
    - 1) Story outline by Robert Bloch, 4/20/67, 10 pgs. 2) Story outline, 4/21/67, 9 pgs. 3) First draft teleplay, 5/15/67, w/annotations, 64 pgs. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bloch, Robert (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Script Materials: DeForest Research (5). Total Items: 5 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence/Inter-office memos: National Broadcasting Company, Desilu Productions, 4/21/67 - 6/19/67. Total Items: 50 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Fontana, D.C. * Coon, Gene * Robertson, Stanley * Messerschmidt, Jean * Justman, Robert (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Financial Materials: Daily Cost Reports (7), Budget & Cost Report (4), Production Budget Reports (2). Total Items: 13 (Box 34, Folder 25)
- CORRESPONDENCE/GENERAL FILES
  - ACKERMAN, FORREST J.
    - Correspondence between Roddenberry and Ackerman, Invitation to Ackerman's birthday, Photos of Fritz Leiber, Correspondence regarding Count Dracula Society's Award. Total Items: 12 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Roddenberry, Gene * Leiber, Fritz (Photo) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - ACTORS, GENERAL
    - General correspondence regarding actors, including a contract, discussions of compensation, work periods, scheduling, and scripts. Total items: 9 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - ADS TV/30
    - Postcard ads, postcard of TV station, NBC promo magazine for TV/30. Total Items: 12 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - AGENCY LISTINGS/SUBMISSIONS
    - Submissions by agencies of lists of actors for consideration for roles. Includes names & pictures. Total items: 72 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - AIR DATE SCHEDULES
    - Schedules listing the title of an episode, its date to be aired, and its production number. Also includes additions to these schedules. Total Items: 25 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - ANDERSON COMPANY
    - Letters to Darrell and Howard Anderson regarding special effects work. Total Items: 17 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - ART DIRECTION
    - Includes: Photos of covers of sci fi magazines, Correspondence between Roddenberry & art directors, Correspondence about art directors. Correspondence between Roddenberry & Louis Drake. Discussion of designs of Star Trek items. Total Items: 27 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Jefferies, Matt * Guzman, Pato * Bachelin, Franz (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - ASHLEY-FAMOUS AGENCY
    - Correspondence between Roddenberry & agents at Ashley-Famous Agency. Total Items: 18 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - ASIMOV, ISAAC
    - Correspondence between Roddenberry & S.F. writer Isaac Asimov, and correspondence between Isaac Asimov & Janet Jeppson. Total Items: 52 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Jeppson, Janet (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - BALL, LUCILLE
    - Note from Lucille Ball to Gene Roddenberry. Total Items: 1 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - BARRETT, MAJEL
    - Resume and bio of Majel Barrett, contract, telegram from Barrett wishing luck to Roddenberry, photo of Barrett. Total Items: 12 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - BLACK, JOHN D. F.
    - Correspondence concerning John D. F. Black, memo regarding Mary Stilwell, John D. F. Black's secretary. Total Items: 17 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - BUDGET/FINANCIAL MATTERS
    - Budget reports for series, weekly cost summaries, correspondence regarding allocation of budget, and miscellaneous financial matters. Total Items: 100+ (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - CAMERAMEN
    - Correspondence about prospective cameramen, including Ernest Haller, Connie Hall, Til Gabani & Gene Polito. Correspondence regarding Star Trek cameraman Jerry Finnerman. Total Items: 16 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Finnerman, Jerry (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - CARABATSOS, STEVE
    - Correspondence regarding Steve Carabatsos, Script Supervisor. Total Items: 3 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - CASTING DIRECTOR
    - Correspondence by and about casting director Joe D'Agosta. Correspondence regarding casting director Kerwin Coughlin. Correspondence regarding casting consultant fees. Total Items: 9 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * D'Agosta, Joe (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - General correspondence regarding casting of actors, casting lists of possible actors to employ, cast lists, photos of actors. Total Items: 100+ Includes correspondence regarding or with: * D'Agosta, Joe (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - CHANG, WAH
    - Correspondence regarding Wah Chang. Total Items: 4 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - CHAPNICK, MORRIS
    - Correspondence to & about Morris Chapnick, Roddenberry's production assistant. Total Items: 5 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - CHOREOGRAPHER
    - Memo regarding Penny Romans, Star Trek choreographer. Total Items: 1 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - COON, GENE
    - Correspondence regarding Gene Coon, producer. Total Items: 7 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, MISCELLANEOUS
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, including queries, thank you notes, congratulatory telegrams, recommendations and bills. Total Items: 90 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Justman, Robert * Roddenberry, Gene (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - CREDITS/TITLES
    - Correspondence regarding credits and titles, including: defining position, size and wording of credits, special effects of titles, & credit disputes. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - CREW SHEETS
    - Lists of Star Trek personnel, including name, address & phone #. Total Items: 146 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - DANIELS, MARC
    - Correspondence to and regarding Marc Daniels, director. Total Items: 5 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - DE FOREST RESEARCH
    - Correspondence regarding Kellam De Forest, De Forest Research, De Forest research lists of ship and character names. Total Items: 16 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - DIRECTORS, GENERAL
    - Includes Resumes of directors, lists of directors, directorial commitment sheets, directorial start dates, & correspondence concerning Star Trek directors. Total Items: 75 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - DOOHAN, JAMES
    - Correspondence to and about James Doohan, specifically regarding compensation, NBC policy, and options in contract. Also includes, contract & photo of James Doohan. Total Items: 11 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - DURYEA, PETER
    - List of Duryea's credits, contract, photo of Duryea. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - EMMY AWARDS
    - Correspondence between Gene Coon, Ed Perlstein & Roddenberry & the Academy. Correspondence between & regarding special effects companies & Emmy awards. Lists of actors, directors, writers & crew for nomination. Total Items: 34 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - EPISODE STATUS REPORTS
    - Episode Status Reports: report of title of episode, Production #, Date Aired, and/or status (Completed, principal photography completed, etc). Total Items: 38 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - FAN LETTERS, 1966
    - Star Trek fan letters (from 1966) & their replies. Total items: 71 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Star Trek fan letters (from 1967) & their replies. Total Items: 154 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Trimble, Bjo (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Star Trek fan letters (from 1968 & undated) and their replies. Total Items: 41 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Trimble, Bjo * Anderson, Karen (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Star Trek fan letters to Gene Roddenberry. Total Items: 43 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Star Trek fan letters to Robert Justman by Scott Smith & Karla Schneider & replies. Total Items: 27 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - FARMER, PHILIP JOSE
    - Correspondence between Roddenberry & Farmer, memo about Farmer. Total Items: 5 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - FILM EFFECTS
    - Correspondence from Linwood G. Dunn, President of Film Effects, discussing fees & terms of agreements. Total Items: 7 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - FINANCIAL MATTERS/BUDGET
    - See BUDGET/FINANCIAL MATTERS (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - FONTANA, DOROTHY C.
    - Correspondence regarding Dorothy Fontana, script consultant. Total Items: 8 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - FREIBERGER, FRED
    - Correspondence regarding Fred Freiberger, Co-Producer. Incl. 2-page memo re updates of scripts/episodes in development. Total Items: 3 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - GLEN GLENN SOUND
    - Correspondence about, from, and to Glen Glenn Sound. Total Items: 4 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - GOODWIN, LAUREL
    - Correspondence regarding Goodwin, specifically compensation & credit, option position. Correspondence to Goodwin from Roddenberry. Contract. List of Goodwin's credits. 4 photos of Goodwin. Total Items: 14 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - HASKIN, BYRON
    - Bio of Byron Haskin, Correspondence to and about Byron Haskin & his secretary, Adrienne Ghio. Photo of ?. Total Items: 6 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - HELLSTROM, ROBERT
    - Memos and correspondence between Hellstrom and Roddenberry. Resumes of Hellstrom and Donald Rea. Mileage Reports. Total Items: 20. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Rea, Donald (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - HOYT, JOHN
    - List of Hoyt's credits, Correspondence between Hoyt and Roddenberry, Contract and modification. Total Items: 8 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - HUNTER, JEFF
    - Bio of Jeff Hunter, Correspondence to and about Jeff Hunter, newspaper clipping reviewing Hunter, 2 8x10 color photos of Hunter, 33 Strips of film for light tests. Total Items: 45 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - JASON, BEN
    - Correspondence between Ben Jason and Roddenberry. Total Items: 3 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - JUSTMAN, ROBERT
    - Correspondence to, by, and about Robert Justman. Total Items: 41 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - KELLEY, DEFOREST
    - Correspondence to & about DeForest Kelley, article on Kelley. Total Items: 19 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - KOENIG, WALTER
    - Correspondence regarding Walter Koenig. Total Items: 3 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - LEGAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to legal matters, including unsolicited screenplays, foreign co-production, and copyright changes. Total Items: 11 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - LENARD, MARK
    - Bio of Lenard, discussion of bio. (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - LOCATIONS
    - List of possible locations, Brochure of Apacheland Studio, Arizona Highways magazine checked for locations. Total Items: 3 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - LOCKWOOD, GARY
    - Bio of Gary Lockwood, letter from Roddenberry to Lockwood. Total Items: 5 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - LONG, ROY
    - Letter of thanks to Long from Roddenberry, memo to Herb Solow from Roddenberry regarding Long's raise. Total Items: 2 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - LUCAS, JOHN MEREDYTH
    - Deal memo for Lucas & supplement to deal memo. Total Items: 2 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - LYNN, HARVEY
    - Correspondence to, from, and regarding Harvey Lynn, Technical Consultant from Rand corporation. Total Items: 50 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - MAKEUP
    - Photos of Nimoy and Majel Barrett in partial makeup, correspondence between Roddenberry & Fred Phillips, mostly regarding makeup & hair. Total Items: 31 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Phillips, Fred * Nimoy, Leonard (photo) * Barrett, Majel (photo) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - MERCHANDISING
    - Correspondence regarding the production and licensing of Star Trek merchandise. Correspondence often involves Licensing Corporation of America & AMT (models). Total Items: 92 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Whitfield, Steve (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - MILKIS, EDWARD
    - Correspondence to and about Edward Milkis, specifically employment and compensation. Total Items: 5 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Miscellaneous items, including memos and correspondence, Douglas progress report, Enterprise interior designs, correspondence involving definition of symbols etc. in Star Trek, poetry, speeches, Time magazine, office concerns. Total Items: 91 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - MUSIC
    - Correspondence regarding music and composers: scheduling, compensation, availabilities of composers, and discussions of music. Also includes sheet music for theme song. Total Items: 73 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - N.A.S.A.
    - Correspondence to and from officers at N.A.S.A., Goddard News newsletter, correspondence from the National Space Club. Total Items: 18 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - N.B.C.
    - Correspondence to and from N.B.C. regarding pre-emption, comments from the network, Broadcast standard and practices, complaints to N.B.C., thank you letters. Total Items: 100+ (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - NARRATION - STANDARD OPENING
    - Rough drafts of opening narration, memos regarding narration. Total Items: 9 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS
    - Assorted newspaper clippings, magazines & photocopies of clippings pertaining to the show. Total Items: 88 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - NICHOLS, NICHELLE
    - Letter to Roddenberry from Nichelle Nichols, Letter to Nichelle Nichols from Roddenberry, Memos regarding Nichols, specifically compensation. Total Items: 9 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - NIMOY, LEONARD
    - Correspondence regarding Leonard Nimoy, specifically contract renegotiations, public appearances, working as director, itineraries, credits, agreements. Also includes contracts, bio, newspaper clippings, list of credits, and 2 photos. Total Items: 53 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - PERSONNEL
    - Correspondence, mostly personnel suggestions, also includes resumes and replies. Total Items: 65 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - PEVNEY, JOSEPH
    - Correspondence regarding Joseph Pevney, specifically shooting dates and compensation. Total Items: 7 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - POST, KEYES, & GARDNER
    - Thank you letter from Jan Miller of Post, Keyes & Gardner. Total Items: 1 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - POST-PRODUCTION, EDITING
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence regarding editing & Star Trek's editing department. Total Items: 17 Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Heath, Bill (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - POST-PRODUCTION, GENERAL
    - Format for show, correspondence regarding post-production, post-production costs, film processes, Golden Reel awards. Post-production schedules, budgets. Total Items: 74 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - PRE-PRODUCTION, GENERAL
    - Miscellaneous correspondence involving pre-production, including information on scripts, story outlines, story approval, and commentary on stories. Total Items: 28 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - PRESENTATIONS
    - Includes a rough draft presentation for the series, lists of sample story lines, letter explaining star formula. Total Items: 19 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - PRODUCTION COSTS
    - Includes only Weekly Production Status Reports which list episode, series budget, episode budget, estimated finish cost, and variances. Total Items: 100+ (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding production, including production sequence, show format, hiatus information, stage information, and thank you notes. Total Items: 31 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - PROJECT VISTA
    - Correspondence regarding Project Vista, charity project coordinated by Roddenberry. Correspondence regards the sale of raffle tickets, the winners of raffle tickets, and correspondence between Roddenberry & Rev. Paul Martin. Total Items: 35 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - PROPS
    - Correspondence regarding the design, creation, and cost of props, incl. phaser weapons/gun. Total Items: 30 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - PUBLICATION TIE-INS